<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KEEVITAJA</title>
    <description>Some words on various subjects. Mostly IT related!</description>
    <link>http://keevitaja.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://keevitaja.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 23:41:46 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 23:41:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Selective abstraction does not make sense</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In Laravel community lot of people use Repository pattern by Taylor Otwell and at the same time they have no problem with using third party packages tightly coupled to their codebase. This kind of selective abstraction makes no sense!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://keevitaja.github.io/2014/11/02/selective-abstraction.html&quot;&gt;Continue reading …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Laravel community lot of people use &lt;a href=&quot;http://ryantablada.com/post/the-repository-pattern-in-action&quot;&gt;Repository pattern&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://taylorotwell.com/&quot;&gt;Taylor Otwell&lt;/a&gt;. At the same time they have no problem with using third party packages tightly coupled to their codebase. This kind of selective abstraction makes no sense!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-origin-of-repository-pattern-in-laravel&quot;&gt;The origin of Repository pattern in Laravel.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course Taylor did not come up with the pattern itself. In his book “&lt;a href=&quot;https://leanpub.com/laravel&quot;&gt;From Apprentice To Artisan&lt;/a&gt;” he talked about it and many people figured it is the right way to do things in &lt;a href=&quot;http://laravel.com/&quot;&gt;Laravel&lt;/a&gt;. Did Taylor really tell us to use this pattern with each application? I do not think so. Most, if not all, coding patterns are optional. To use different patterns in our projects we have to select them according to the projects scale and the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-should-we-consider-the-repository-pattern&quot;&gt;Why should we consider the Repository pattern?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally abstraction is a good practice and so is the Repository pattern if we are working on a large scale project. The reason to have it, is simple. One day there might be a need to swap out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://laravel.com/docs/4.2/eloquent&quot;&gt;Eloquent&lt;/a&gt; with another database driver. If our database layer is abstracted the swapping process can go with less pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how likely will we need to swap out the Eloquent? In most cases not likely. Eloquent supports many database services, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mysql.com/&quot;&gt;MySQL&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postgresql.org/&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps we would need to swap out Eloquent if we want to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mongodb.org/&quot;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; which works well with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hierarchical_database_model&quot;&gt;hierarchical data&lt;/a&gt;. In most cases we can stick happily with Eloquent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;selective-abstraction-does-not-make-sense&quot;&gt;Selective abstraction does not make sense!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have seen too many times the following situation. Developer is using Repositories with &lt;a href=&quot;http://laravel.com/docs/4.2/ioc&quot;&gt;interface binding&lt;/a&gt;. He is also using some third party packages, like image manipulator, which are not abstracted in any way. Does this make any sense?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when i ask this developer why is he using Repositories, i usually do not get a straight answer. Perhaps some gibberish about Repositories being a good practice or something. Also i have seen projects that use Repositories returning the Eloquent object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your Repository returns Eloquent object, your code is still tightly coupled to Eloquent driver and you have accomplished nothing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is just stupid!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it would make sense to abstract everything and prepare for everything. To use only Repositories is 100% senseless!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://keevitaja.github.io/2014/11/02/selective-abstraction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://keevitaja.github.io/2014/11/02/selective-abstraction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Patterns</category>
        
        <category>Laravel</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello voodoo people</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah, i do not know much about voodoo. So in this blog i mostly concentrate on things i do know - things like how to make some cool stuff on the web, which tools to use and of course Ubuntu Linux which i love! As i am not native a english speaker, i hope you forgive me all the spelling and styling mistakes i will make. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2014/11/01/hello-voodoo-people.html&quot;&gt;Continue reading …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, i do not know much about &lt;a href=&quot;http://voodoo.net&quot;&gt;voodoo&lt;/a&gt;. So in this blog i mostly concentrate on things i do know - things like how to make some cool stuff on the web, which tools to use and of course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Linux&lt;/a&gt; which i love! As i am not a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Estonian_language&quot;&gt;native&lt;/a&gt; english speaker, i hope you forgive me all the spelling and styling mistakes i will make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-tech-department-of-this-blog&quot;&gt;The tech department of this blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When i started to think about creating a personal blog, the first thing i looked for was a simple theme and easy to use blog engine. I have made several webpages using &lt;a href=&quot;http://pyrocms.com&quot;&gt;PyroCMS&lt;/a&gt; and also have some experience with &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, but none of theme had a suitable theme for personal blogging. So i had to write something that suits my needs - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/keevitaja/publisher&quot;&gt;Publisher theme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To write the Publisher &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/html5/&quot;&gt;HTML5&lt;/a&gt; theme, i used tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gulpjs.com/&quot;&gt;Gulp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://compass-style.org/&quot;&gt;Compass&lt;/a&gt; with its extension and other &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/explore&quot;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt; projects. As i could not find a simple blog engine, i decided to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; static page generator. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In time i will blog about all these tools as on many occasions the official documentation sucks big time! Like with Jekyll i had to &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com&quot;&gt;google&lt;/a&gt; a lot, to get the job done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-writing-department&quot;&gt;The writing department&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For coding i use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/&quot;&gt;Sublime text 3&lt;/a&gt; editor with several &lt;a href=&quot;https://sublime.wbond.net/&quot;&gt;extensions&lt;/a&gt; and personal customization. For posting i use &lt;a href=&quot;http://uberwriter.wolfvollprecht.de/&quot;&gt;UberWriter&lt;/a&gt; markdown editor. And yes, my OS of choice is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu Linux&lt;/a&gt; 14.04 LTS. Believe it or not, but it is better than a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/mac/&quot;&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W--13mBc788&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; does not qualify as an operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-to-expect&quot;&gt;What to expect?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect to see lot of posts on all subjects mentioned above. Also lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://laravel.com&quot;&gt;Laravel&lt;/a&gt; and general &lt;a href=&quot;http://php.net&quot;&gt;PHP&lt;/a&gt; stuff. It is extremely unlikely you will see here anything about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.britneyspears.com/&quot;&gt;Britney Spears&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.christinaaguilera.com/&quot;&gt;Christina Aguilera&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have some comments or suggestions, leave them below, and i’ll come back to you ASAP.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 19:07:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://keevitaja.github.io/2014/11/01/hello-voodoo-people.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://keevitaja.github.io/2014/11/01/hello-voodoo-people.html</guid>
        
        <category>General</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
